Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. 16mm Microfilm Investigations, 1913-1950 and undated
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- 16mm Investigations, 1913-1950 and undated
  - Planter's Peanuts
    - Check of distribution and sales position of Planter's and competitive peanuts in Washington, Buffalo, Hartford, and Nashville, 1935 Aug.
    - Investigation in Terre Haute, Ind., 1935 Nov.
    - Results of test advertising and detailing in 6 cities and analysis of drug confectionary and tobacco stores business in 18 metropolitan markets, 1937 Apr.
    - Color comics--sales trend (Feb.-1935 Oct.), 1935 Nov.-Dec.
    - Planter's sales--Glassine vs. bags, 1935 Dec.
    - Planter's sales (1935), 1936 June
    - Greater Boston market, 1938 Feb.
    - Results in Planter's advertising test cities, 1938 Aug.
    - Planter's Peanuts postcard survey--Wilkes-Barre, 1941 Apr.
    - Office survey on peanuts, 1941 Apr.
    - Survey in subway stations, 1941 Apr.
    - Consumer survey on ideas for entertainment, 1941 May
    - Subway Union news stands check, 1941 Sept.
    - Postcard survey on Planter's Cocktail Peanuts (Dec. 1, 1942), 1942 Jan.
  - Pond's Extract Co. (Lamont, Corliss, and Co.) (see also reels 52, 53)
    - Test of Pond's powder (#54 and #79), 1934 Oct.
    - Dealer investigation of the shaving cream market, 1934 Nov.
    - Consumer blind test of Pond's cold cream vs. Lady Esther, 1934 Nov.
    - Division of Pond's sales by outlets (all products), 1934 Nov.
    - Pond's powder test on perfume, 1935 Jan.
    - Pond's powder test on texture, 1935 Jan.
    - Test of five face powders (L-0, l-2, l-3, l-4, l-5), 1935 Feb.
    - Test of two face powders (8 and 9), 1935 Feb.
    - Office test on Pond's cold cream, 1935 Feb.
    - Report on Pond's new suntan powder, 1935 Mar.
    - Office test on Pond's cold cream (#5 and #9), 1935 Aug.
    - Office investigation on depilatories, 1935 Nov.
    - Test on new formula of cold cream and Vanishing Cream, 1936 Jan.
  - Standard Brands, Inc. (see also reels 49, 54-58, 196, 197)
    - Net earnings compared to advertising expenditures of 3 leading tobacco manufacturers (1930-34), 1935 Sept.
    - Earnings of Canadian companies--Hudson, Loblaw, and Eaton, 1935 Sept.
    - Study of U.S. market for yerba mate, 1935 Nov.
    - Peanut butter--volume, gross margin, etc., 1935 Nov.
    - Memo to Mr. Baillie regarding Diastafor, 1936 May
    - Advertising analysis by bakery products and grocery products, 1936 June
    - Comparison of federal relief expenditures with federal income tax revenue by states, 1936 June
    - Analysis of 1936 advertising costs by divisions, 1936 June
    - Advertising expenditures of General Foods, Procter & Gamble, 1936 July
    - Summary of information on Junket, 1936 July
    - Report on metabolized vitamin D milk sales promotion questions, 1936 July
    - Advertising analysis for 1936, 1936
    - Analysis of average monthly salaries of standard brand employees by regions and divisions, 1936 Dec.
    - Analysis of advertising expenditures by divisions--all products (first 6 months of 1937), 1937 June
  - J.B. Williams Co. (see also reel 60)
    - Audit bureau sales reports, 1941
    - Rochester--lather creams, 1941
    - Rochester--brushless creams, 1941
    - Rochester--lotion, 1941
    - Providence--lather creams, 1941
    - Providence--brushless creams, 1941
    - Providence--lotion, 1941
    - Indianapolis--lather creams, 1941
    - Indianapolis--brushless creams, 1941
    - Indianapolis--lotion, 1941
    - Atlanta--lather creams, 1941
    - Atlanta--brushless creams, 1941
    - Atlanta--lotion, 1941
  - A. Guinness Son and Co. Ltd.
    - Dealer investigation on price of Guinness stout and Bass ale, 1937 Oct.
    - Effect of local advertising on sales of Guinness, 1937 Oct.
    - Dealer investigation on price of Guinness stout and Bass ale in San Francisco, 1937 Nov.
    - Survey of Guinness distribution and prices in N.Y. City, 1938 Jan.
    - Analysis of doctors' comments on bulletins, 1938 July (Reel 222)
    - Dealer telephone survey in Chicago, 1938 July
    - Consumer mail survey, 1939 May
    - Sales check of Guinness in 14 retail outlets (May-1939 Sept.), 1939 Oct.
  - Andrew Jergens Co. (see also reels 45, 46, 196)
    - Woodbury consumer investigation in N.Y. City--Pittsfield and Cincinnati, 1930 Jan.
    - Report of 10 women who have used the new Woodbury facial soap, 1930 Mar.
    - Report of 10 women who have used the new Woodbury formula, 1930 Mar.
    - Combined report on new formula, 1930 Apr.
    - Jergens lotion sales analysis, 1928-30, 1930 Apr.
    - Woodbury soap and Jergens lotion coupon analysis, 1930 Apr.
    - Analysis of Woodbury's facial soap coupon returns by size of city, 1930 Apr.
    - Analysis of Jergens lotion coupon returns, 1930 June
    - Reactions to Woodbury radio program, 1931 Nov.
    - Jergens bath tablet--office test, 1931 Dec.
  - International Investigations
    - Argentina
      - Propaganda, 1930
      - Study of press treatment--British trade fair, 1931
      - Study of press attitude toward U.S., 1931
      - All America cables report, 1929 June
      - Drug investigation (Argentina), 1929 June
      - Drug investigations (Buenos Aires, exhibit C), 1929
      - Report of recommendations and investigation (Frigidaire), 1929
      - Survey and analysis of the Argentine market, produced by the J. Walter Thompson Company for General Motors Argentina (advertising division, general sales department, General Motors export division), 1929
      - General Motors Argentina--Report of investigation and recommendations for advertising--Buenos Aires Office, 1929
      - Volume I--Report on the city of Buenos Aires (survey made at the request of General Motors Argentina, S.A.), 1929
      - Volume II--Report on the city of Rosario, 1929
      - Volume III--Report on the city of La Plata, 1929
      - Volume IV--Report on the city of Mendoza, 1929
      - Goodrich recommendations, 1929 Oct.-1930 Jan.
      - Plan of institutional advertising--the Great Central Argentine Railway, 1931 Nov.
      - Report on Horlicks malted milk, 1929
      - Analysis of questionnaires referring to milk consumed by householders in Buenos Aires, dated Sept. 24, 1930, Henry Martin and Co., Avenida Roque Saenz Pena 570, B.A., 1929
      - Study of coupon returns, Kelito contest for Noel and Cia., 1929
      - Analisis de cupones del concurso de chocolatines Kelito, 1929
      - Memorandum Noel and Cia. Ltd. advertising recommendations for advertising, 1929
      - Noel and Cia. report of investigation and recommendations for advertising, 1929
      - Investigation on quince jam in packages, 1929
      - Face creams, 1935
      - Face powders, 1935
      - Investigation on pyorrhea--Buenos Aires, 1935
      - Royal baking powder investigation B.A., 1930 Oct. 18
      - Royal baking powder consumer investigation--Argentina, 1931
      - Analysis of questionnaires regarding Royal baking powder--Henry Martin and Co. B.A., 1930 Dec. 11
      - Royal fruit gelatin test--analysis of questionnaires attached--Henry Martin and Co., 1931 Feb. 19
      - Analysis of questionnaires referring to smokers of cigars and cigarettes--Henry Martin and Co. (see also reel 232 for Scott's Emulsion investigation of 1936), 1930 Oct. 3
    - Australia
      - Proposed investigation for Australian Women's Weekly, 1933
      - Woman and woman's weekly reader survey, 1935 Nov.
      - Australian Women's Weekly investigation--Conducted for Sydney Newspapers Ltd., 1933 Aug.
      - Broadcasting stations investigation--A survey of telephone users' preferences, 1934
      - Sydney broadcasting stations--Telephone investigation, 1935 Mar.
      - Confidential report--An inquiry into the influence of wireless programmes on school children--Sydney, Australia, 1935 Feb. 4
      - Market research report--Radio in Australia, undated
      - Bushell's tea investigation--Adelaide, 1930 Dec.
      - Report on Australia (written on cover in blue pencil--Caldwell--Burnet Corp.), 1918
      - Flit--Advertising and merchandising plan, 1930-1931
      - Folder marked: General Motors Sydney Office containing: 1. report. General Motors radio publicity programme. H.R. wearing media manager, 2. schedules marked (by memo attached) General Motors--Don Bradman radio publicity scheme, 1930
      - General Motors Australia Pty. Ltd.--Non-car owner investigation--Australia, undated
      - General Motors investigation--Car owner and car dealer summaries, undated
      - General Motors Australia Pty. Ltd.--G.M.C. truck investigation Australia, undated
      - General Motors Australia Pty. Ltd.--Competitive car owner investigation--Australia, undated
      - General Motors Australia Pty. Ltd.--Competitive truck owner investigation--Australia, undated
      - Car owner investigation--Queensland--Country Downs, undated
      - General Motors Australia Pty. Ltd.--Buick investigation--Australia, undated (Reel 223)
      - Buick plan 1931--General Motors (Australia) Pty. Ltd., undated
      - General Motors Australia Pty. Ltd.--Cadillac and LaSalle investigation--Australia, undated
      - General Motors Australia Pty. Ltd.--Chevrolet investigation--Australia, undated
      - General Motors Australia Pty. Ltd.--Chevrolet truck investigation--Australia, undated
      - Chevrolet and Ford owner report--Victoria, undated
      - General Motors Australia Pty. Ltd.--Oakland investigation--Australia, undated
      - General Motors Australia Pty. Ltd.--Oldsmobile investigation--Australia, undated
      - General Motors Australia Pty. Ltd.--Pontiac investigation--Australia, undated
      - General Motors Australia Pty. Ltd.--Vauxhall investigation--Australia, undated
      - General Motors Australia Pty. Ltd.--Vauxhall programme, 1931
      - Milk food drinks investigation--Australia, 1937 Nov.
      - Jantzen investigation--Australia, undated
      - Johnson outboard motors--Report on information obtained from Johnson agents in Australia, 1930
      - Junket investigation--New South Wales, 1932 Oct.
      - Proposed investigation--Junket tablets, etc., 1932 Oct.
      - Cheese investigation--New South Wales, 1936 Nov.
      - Cheese investigation--Victoria, 1937 Feb.
      - Kraft Walker Cheese Co. Pty. Ltd. advertising plan, 1931
      - Lux investigation, undated
      - Lux toilet soap investigation, undated
      - Report on Pond's creams for Australia, 1930 Aug. 8
      - Radio--Owner investigation--Sydney (Pond's creams), 1932 Aug.
      - Pond's cream investigation--Australia, 1929 Nov. 20
      - Pond's Extract Co. International Ltd. advertising recommendations, 1931-1932
      - Pond's investigation--Dealers, 1931 Jan. 29
      - New South Wales Egg Marketing Board--Advertising programme for sunrise eggs, 1932
      - Daily telegraph reader survey, 1936 Mar.
      - Daily telegraph investigation--Sydney N.S.W., 1932 Aug.
      - Age of accumulation survey, 1937 Nov.
      - Supplementary commodity survey, 1937 Dec.
      - Sydney morning newspapers reader survey, 1936 Feb.
      - Towel investigation--New South Wales, 1936 Dec.
      - Vegemite investigation--Victoria, 1937 Feb.
      - Wine industry in Australia, 1932 May
      - Wrigley investigation amongst Sydney school children, 1936 Aug.
      - Market statistics for Australia, 1931 Sept.
      - Australia and New Zealand basic statistics, 1933
    - Belgium
      - Investigation of Buick advertising Bisset Hall, newspapers, and periodicals, 1929 Sept. 1
      - Motor car study, dealers, Belgium, 1927 Aug.
      - Motor car study, owners, Belgium, 1927 Aug.
      - Commercial vehicle study, owners, Belgium, 1927 Aug.
      - Commercial vehicle study, dealers, Belgium, 1927 Aug.
    - Brazil
      - Investigation made for Blue Star Line, 1931
      - Investigation for Lehn and Fink, Brazil, 1931 May
      - Pond's extract Company, international, Ltd., investigation of the face cream market in Brazil, 1934 July
      - Preliminary report on Royal baking powder from Sao Paulo Office, undated
    - Canada
      - Survey of the Canadian market for household ammonia, 1931 Jan.
      - Facts on Canadian media, 1930 Dec.
      - Consumer survey cameras, 1933 Dec.
      - Confidential Canadian doctors' campaign, permission granted to publish testimonials (Guinness), 1931 (Reel 224)
      - Survey of newspaper reading habits of adolescents, 1938 July
      - Pond's Extract Co. of Canada, Ltd., dealer investigation on price--Cutting situation, 1931 Feb.
      - Standard Brands Limited, survey of the baking powder market in 4 Canadian cities, 1933 June
      - Report on a questionnaire to housewives regarding baking powder, 1934 Oct.
      - Standard Brands Limited, survey among Gillex users in Montreal and Toronto, 1933 Nov.
      - Standard Brands Limited, survey on yeast-cakes in rural Canada, 1934 Aug.
    - Denmark
      - Data re free port of Copenhagen, 1921 Jan. 13
      - Commercial vehicle study, dealers, Denmark, undated
      - Commercial vehicle study, owners, Denmark, undated
      - Motor car study, owners, Denmark, 1927 Sept.
      - Motor car study. dealers, Denmark, 1927 Aug.
      - Report of investigation on wireless, dealers, Denmark, 1928 Feb.
      - Report of investigation on wireless, consumers, Denmark, 1928 Jan.
      - Danish and Norwegian media, Copenhagen, 1931 Sept. 15
    - Egypt
      - Report on the market in Egypt for tea, coffee, yeast, baking powder, and gelatin, 1930 May
      - Horlick's malted milk, Alexandria, 1928
    - Finland
      - Motor car study (Owners--Dealers), commercial vehicle study (Dealers), 1927 Aug.
      - Motor car study, owners, Finland, 1927 Aug.
    - France
      - Bromo-Seltzer, report on A.W.B. Scott, Paris, undated
      - Buick--Marquette analysis of dealer questionnaires, 1929 Nov.
      - Cine Kodak merchandising recommendations, 1931 June
      - Commercial vehicle study, dealers, France, 1927 Aug.
      - Commercial vehicle study, owners, France, 1927 Aug.
      - Gillette investigation, consumers, 1930 Apr.
      - Gillette investigation, dealers, 1930 Apr.
      - Enquete Goodrich, 1930 Jan.
      - Report on Dorothy Gray, dealers' investigation, 1929 Sept.
      - Possibilities of Horlick's malted milk in France, parts I and II, 1930 May
      - Possibilities of Horlick's malted milk in France, parts III, 1930 May
      - Horlick's investigation, dealers--Paris and Lille, 1930 May
      - Report of meeting on mayonnaise, Paris Office, 1930 Sept. 25
      - Pond's supplementary investigation, 1937 Aug.
      - Marketing data, France, 1929 May
    - Germany
      - Motor car study, owners, Germany, 1927 Sept.
      - Commercial vehicle study, Chevrolet dealers, Germany, 1927 Nov.
      - Commercial vehicle study, dealers, Germany, 1927 Sept.
      - Commercial vehicle study, Chevrolet truck owners, Berlin, 1929 Aug.
      - Commercial vehicle study. potential owners, Germany, 1927 Sept.
      - Commercial vehicle study, owners, Germany, 1927 Sept.
      - Motor car study, potential owners, Germany, 1927 Sept.
      - Report of media investigation amongst car owners and dealers, Germany, 1927 Oct.
      - Additional information on media investigation, Germany, 1927 Nov.
      - Commercial vehicle study, potential Chevrolet truck owners, Berlin, 1929 Aug.
      - Memorandum on Pond's in Germany: 1. recommendations for fall, 1932, 2. review of Pond's, 1929 to data, 3. sales figures, etc.,. 1929 to date, 1929-1932
      - Investigation on skin care: consumers--Germany, 1932 May, analysis and tabulation of findings, 1932 May
      - Investigation on skin care: consumers--Germany, 1932 May, detailed reports of interviews with consumers, 1932 May
      - Folder marked: Pond's investigation, Germany, 1932
      - The German press, 1929 Feb.
      - Analysis of the market possibilities of Royal baking powder in Germany, 1930 Jan.
      - German milline rates, 1929
    - Great Britain
      - Folder: cheese, 1925-1927
      - Report of Cutex investigation in England and Scotland, 1932 Feb.-Mar.
      - Cutex advertising plan in England, 1927
      - General Motors Ltd. investigation, car dealers, Great Britain, 1927 June
      - 1927-1928 advertising plan, Chevrolet commercial vehicle, Great Britain, 1927-1928
      - Preliminary report of investigation among Vauxhall dealers, undated
      - Preliminary report of investigation among Vauxhall car owners (Personal interview and mail), 1927 June
      - Vauxhall, general data, Vauxhall export division, London, 1929 Oct. 1
      - Commercial vehicle study, owners, United Kingdom, 1927 July
      - Commercial vehicle study, dealers, England, Scotland, and Wales, 1927 June
      - Short summary on Harpic, 1933 June (Reel 225)
      - Short summary of results of national investigation into the consumption of herrings, 1934 June
      - Report of investigation on Jantzen bathing suits, consumers, London, 1930 July
      - Folder: Jell-O, British market, 1922-1924
      - Folder: Libby, McNeil, and Libby, Ltd. (contains five reports), 1933
      - Review of some distribution problems, Marconiphone, 1930 Feb.
      - Folder: Melereon hair dye, London, 1939 Apr. 27
      - Report of investigation amongst women on use of depilatories and razors, 1929-1931
      - Report of investigation on Odorono, women, London, exhibit D, 1929 Sept.
      - Pond's test campaigns, 1932 Apr.
      - Information on Australian, English, and American creams, 1932
      - Folder: Pond's Extract Co., London Office data, etc., 1931
      - Summary of six months progress with Pond's Extract Co., 1932
      - Results of investigation on face creams (with special reference to Princess Marguerite all-purpose cream), 1937 July
      - Report of investigation on beauty treatments with special reference to face creams, Great Britain, 1934 Nov.
      - Investigation for O'Sullivan's rubber heels in Great Britain, undated
      - Report of investigation on stok consumers, Nottingham and Sheffield, 1931 May
      - Report on consumer investigation on soup consumption, 1926
      - Appraisal of opportunity to market new brand of tea in United Kingdom, undated
      - Report of the International Tea Committee (printed in London), 1933 July 1-1934 Mar. 31
      - Report of investigation on tea, London, 1928 Oct.
      - Report on the uses given in short letter competition for Vaseline petroleum jelly, 1927 Nov.
      - Washing tests reports (15 folders containing specimens of washed materials attached), undated
      - Survey of the British market for Woodbury's facial soap, 1922
      - England--Trade interviews (see reel 232 for more investigations), 1925
    - Holland
      - Motor car study, owners, Holland, 1927 Aug.
      - Motor car study, dealers, Holland, 1927 Aug.
      - Commercial vehicle study, owners, Holland, 1927 Aug.
      - Commercial vehicle study, dealers, Holland, 1927 Aug.
      - Automobile report for Holland in 1928, 1928
    - India
      - Report on India, Burma and Ceylon compiled on the basis of Mesars, Lehn and Fink's questionnaire, 1931 June
      - Wholesale price list--G.M. Moledina and Co., wholesale perfumers and general merchandise, direct importers of foreign perfumery, Bombay, 1929
      - Seth Thomas clock investigation in Bombay, India, 1929
    - Japan
      - The Japan market (for toilet preparations, disinfectants, etc.), report for the Lehn and Fink Co. in answer to questionnaire, 1931
    - New Zealand
      - Lehn and Fink drug investigation, New Zealand, 1931
    - Norway
      - The Lehn and Fink Company, N.Y., market investigation in Norway, 1931 June 1
      - Motor car study, owners, Norway, 1927 Aug.
      - Motor car study, dealers, Norway, 1927 Aug.
      - Commercial vehicle study, dealers, Norway, 1927 Sept.
      - Commercial vehicle study, owners, Norway, 1927 Sept.
    - Poland
      - Automobile survey of Poland, prepared for General Motors by JWT Co., Warsaw, undated
      - Commercial vehicle study, owners and dealers, Poland, undated
      - Motor car study, owners, Poland, 1927 Sept.
      - Motor car study, dealers, Poland, undated
    - South Africa
      - Port Elizabeth Office, past and future, 1931
      - Report for Lehn and Fink, 1931 Sept.
      - Royal baking powder, report on clarification of media--Port Elizabeth, undated
      - Unguentine in the South African market--Port Elizabeth, 1929
    - Spain
      - The electric appliance situation in Spain, 1930 Nov. 27
      - Truck study and recommendations, Spain, 1931 Jan. 19
      - Motor car study, owners, Spain, 1927 July
      - Motor car study, dealers, Spain, 1927 July
      - Commercial vehicle study, owner and dealer, Spain, 1927 July
      - Motor car study, owners, Oldsmobile and Chevrolet, Spain, 1927 Sept.
    - Sweden (see also reel 232)
      - Chain store operation, Stockholm, undated
      - Analysis of Chevrolet owners by occupation, city of Stockholm, Sweden, 1927
      - Report on small--Car owner investigation in Stockholm, 1929 Sept.
      - Motor car study, owners, Sweden, 1927 Sept.
      - Motor car study, dealers, Sweden, 1927 Sept.
      - Trade in investigation (Cars), Sweden, 1930 Jan. 22
      - General Motors consumer investigation passenger cars, 1930 Oct.
      - Motor car study (Owners--Dealers), commercial vehicle study (Dealers), 1927 Sept.
  - Calsodent Co. Inc.
    - Investigation, 1929-1943 (Reel 230)
  - Lever Bros. Co.
    - Pears soap, 1931-1933
  - P. Lorillard Co.
    - Old Gold cigarettes, 1941-1944
  - Boston Globe
    - Portfolio on eighth floor (newspaper ads--too big for 16mm film), 1935-1943
  - Investigations
    - New Business (original copy sent to London), 1945 Nov.
    - Report on tourist travel to France and other countries, 1937 June
  - Portfolios
    - The Odorono Co., 1915-1916
    - The Odorono Co., 1916-1944 (Reel 231)
  - International Investigations
    - Sweden (cont. from reel 225)
      - Chevrolet owner investigation, Sweden, 1929 (Reel 232)
      - Folder containing papers re: Swedish market investigation on Kellogg, 1939
      - Report of sales on Lux toilet soap, 1930 June
      - Plan for Pond's campaign, Sweden, 1932
      - Pond's report on consumer investigation, Stockholm and Orebro, 1929 Oct.
    - Switzerland
      - Commercial vehicle study, owners, Switzerland, 1927 Aug.
      - Commercial vehicle study, dealers, Switzerland, 1927 Aug.
      - Motor car study, dealers, Switzerland, 1927 Aug.
      - Motor car study, owners, Switzerland, 1927 Aug.
    - Uruguay
      - Folder: face cream investigation, Montevideo, undated
      - Survey of the retail face cream market, Montevideo, exhibit E, 1930 Jan.
      - Montevideo passenger car survey, 1930 Jan.
      - Montevideo truck survey, 1930 Jan.
      - General Motors Uruguaya, S.A., report of investigations, 1930 Jan.
      - Survey of the retail face cream market, Montevideo, 1930 Jan.
    - Argentina (see also reel 222 for other investigations)
      - Buenos Aires--Scott's emulsion, 1936 Dec.
    - Germany (see also reel 224 for other investigations)
      - Advertising in Germany--It's Nature--A.E. Hobbs, 1928
      - Basic data--Berlin, 1930
    - Great Britain (see reels 224 and 225 for other investigations)
      - Royal baking powder--Analysis of canvass in Ireland and Scotland, 1929
      - Baking powder--Pre-survey of English market, 1925
      - Representative advertisements--London, 1936
      - Absorbine Jr.--London--Consumers and dealers, 1929
      - London--Testing ideas and methods by localised sales, 1937
      - London--Dentifrice market in United Kingdom and notes on historical developments, 1939
    - India (see also reel 225 for other investigations)
      - Notes on Indian advertising, Bombay, 1938